so how do you realistically break past
burnout and overwhelm as a coach or
mentor and only have to work maybe 10 to
15 hours a week and have a sustainable
six or even seven figure business that's
exactly what I'm going to be talking
about here today and I'm going to be
giving you some strategies that I use
that work in my business they're updated
for 2024 what's working right now
through our testing working with
business owners and our coaching group
as well as what you can apply by the end
of this video to get results now for the
those you that I haven't met yet my name
is Jeremiah Kowski and I have built
multiple coaching businesses over the
last 21 years to over $10 million per
year in profit and what I do is every
single day is I help coaches mentors
authors and speakers scale their
businesses successfully I actually
didn't get my start intending to be a
coach to coaches that actually happened
super organically I was thinking about
this the other day is I started and I
just want wanted to be a video editor I
actually had a dream to go to Hollywood
and tell stories in movies and and I
still enjoy storytelling to this day
it's a big part of how we do our
marketing and what I Mentor people in is
how to tell extremely well stories that
close sales fast forward I was doing
that in the same industry for 21 years
and then it turned into me being like
okay I've helped thousands of people be
successful I've been very successful in
building these businesses I'm going to
focus Fus everything in helping people
that want to get their word out there
become a thought leader Mentor trainer
and reach everybody as well as how do
they grow uh their sales how do they get
more leads how do they get more people
signing up for their stuff all of that
put together combined turned into what I
do today and that's exactly how I help
people and so but I do so without
burnout without working hundreds of
hours a week without having to spend a
ton of time to get everything done I
don't spend hundreds of hours working
now could I sure but I've chosen that I
don't want to live that life because
it's not sustainable that's something I
want to tell you is that if you even
though you can maybe temporarily it
might make sense to grind or push
yourself for a certain period of time to
do things to get stuff done but it's not
sustainable longterm as a lifestyle to
be working hundreds and hundreds of
hours and often times it comes from
feeling like I have to work this much in
order to be worthy of the kind of money
that I want to make can I tell you this
two things okay inflation is real and no
matter who gets elected no matter what's
happening it's only going to become more
as far as that goes and so today
everything costs it feels like at least
50 to 100% more than it was 3 years ago
in fact the numbers show that minimum
most everything that we buy is at least
50% more than it was 3 years ago I
actually seen the reports on this and so
realizing that you you might be thinking
in numbers in terms of money in a
business based on three years ago
numbers oh I can just have a $50,000 a
year business I think you need to be
making at least $1 to $150,000 to be
able to buy a house to able to get
approved especially with a business and
a loan you got to be able to have
showable income that shows that you're
doing at least about 120 $50,000 so all
that to say is that needs to be your
your focus and your goal is how do we
get that Revenue up to that place where
we're making profit at that point so
that we can sustain things so that it's
a long-term thing that we can keep doing
bring in more business bring in more
sales and help more people the problem
is is that you can work a lot to do this
and then you're essentially being paid
like 10 bucks an hour who wants to build
a business and only be paid 10 bucks an
hour right not me and and and and that's
exactly what ends up happening as far as
that goes now sure some of the business
that we built they made over $10 million
a year and you might be saying well if I
was making $10 million a year I'd work
a100 hours a week can I tell you
this the the people and the businesses
that make that much do so by not working
all the time by actually spending time
for having fun spending time with their
families and they've learned how to
systematize their time so they're not
doing all of this busy work they're not
working in the business they focus in on
the strategy and they got two things
there's two things that end up happening
okay we're going to go over here to the
Whiteboard here number
one efficiency okay so efficiency is
something that that I have been called
one of the one of the Masters of is
getting more with less work getting more
done with less work in businesses if I
can get the same amount of output for
way less input it is better all the time
to do that lower input as far as that
goes and to find what we call that sort
of Sweet Spot it's kind of like okay we
have inputs but there's diminishing
returns as we do that I like to find The
Sweet Spot before the returns diminish
and this basically goes based on our
energy input we all have a limited
amount of time in our lifetimes if we
look at that but also time in our weeks
and time in our our days as far as that
goes now if you're single you don't have
kids you got more time you know when I
was married without kids I had more time
now got two kids and and it's like okay
I don't have enough time how do I get
more efficient so that a I I don't come
at it 15 years from now and I missed
them growing up and I spent all my time
grinding to build a business to provide
a life for what they want and I missed
actually spending time with my kids I
don't want that to
happen and and and and yet that's the
story of a lot of business owners and so
you're never going to hear me pushing
that you're going to hear me pushing
efficiency for the best most profitable
result in your business and this is the
other thing too is you have to make
profit
important yes how you make your money is
important being unethical doing things
that are immoral and lack Integrity is
not something that I would encourage you
to do nor should I say that you should
do and you know I I read a great book I
was reading the other day it's like if
that was the case we would look at the
mafia and be like wow they're really
good at what they do because they make a
lot of
money but it's like no they're not how
they made their money is not good right
as far as that goes so it's like it's
not just profit for profit sake as far
as that goes it matters how you make it
but you got to find where that this
needs to be a priority so you need to
focus more on profit over everything
else in your business and I think this
is where a lot of coaches and mentors
get it wrong because they're looking at
okay well I want to have impact and
these are people and they have hearts
and souls and minds and I really want to
help them as far as that goes but can I
tell you this that there's actually a
combo of when you're making the most
amount of profit you can roll that back
into the business and then that turns
into more impact as far as that goes so
your profit going up actually equals
more impact because it circles right
back into efficiency if I'm making more
profit I can do one of the most amazing
things which is hiring some people
people to work for me that can optimize
my time so that I don't have to work 40
hours a week I can hire somebody for 30
of that time to take over a lot of those
things and you might be saying well I
don't want to deal with people I don't
want to deal with hiring people or
employees or staff and sometimes that's
an area where we need to say okay maybe
we don't have skill maybe we need to
grow into doing what we feel
uncomfortable doing maybe we need to
learn a new skill so that we can have
the life that we want to live that's
different than what we want and then
some of you might be saying well first
off Jeremiah I don't have profit to be
able to be efficient so how the heck can
I make this
happen and this is one of my favorite
areas that I think once you get it it
changes everything for you because in
the beginning for beginners this is what
is very important is learning how to
control your
thoughts learning the emotional
self-control to where you don't allow
yourself to be
distracted and you learn to
control your
attention your own attention where do
you put your attention where do you put
your focus and I used to really hate the
word Focus for so long in this whole
topic of controlling your attention and
I realized as well like we live in a
world today that really pushes this idea
of ADHD an adult ADHD if you looked at
me I had the symptoms of it for for
years as far as that goes that they
actually have found that people that
might quote unquote have ADHD symptoms
actually are better business owners
longterm as far as that goes so turn
what might seem like a limitation into
your superpower here's the thing in
today's world everything is vying for
our attention right now on the side of
this video there are multiple other
videos right next to me that could
distract you that you could click on and
go watch and not listen to me you might
be scrolling social media while you're
watching me listening in the background
paying attention to other things as far
as that goes how many of y'all did I
expose what you're doing right now
exactly and it's because that's the
world that we live in and so now more
than ever controlling our attention and
our thoughts and our feelings our
emotional feelings are a very very
important powerful part of our life you
know when I started in business we
didn't have so much um trying to get our
our our attention off or to throw us off
emot Al the algorithms weren't tuned
with incredibly powerful AI that were
intended to divide and conquer and
distract Us in order to amplify ad
revenue for the creators of these
algorithms and these platforms as far as
that goes now that's a whole other topic
for another another time the ethics of
that these are businesses that have to
make money and so they've designed these
mechanisms in there you got to make your
brain more powerful than the platforms
that you're on the number one one way to
actually reach clients is through social
media and I think that's one of the
things that we have to learn to get good
at is we have to learn how to
become
Master
communicators okay and people who are
also Master
connectors so communication and
connection and the ability to
communicate and again you might say
Jeremiah who the heck do you think you
are to tell me I'm not good at
communication I don't mean any
disrespect at all to you and I promise
that cuz I know this might come across
that way to some of you what I mean is
that there is a way of communicating
that's more
efficient if you have to tell an
employee or a staff member 10 times how
to get something done versus you learn a
different way to communicate so they get
it done the first time that's a skill
and there's literally ways to gain that
skill as far as that goes in my coaching
program we actually work with you on how
to be able to grow in these skills to be
able to build a business to be able to
reach people to be able to communicate
in a powerful way that is effective that
produces results and you can find that
over at my website over at Jeremiah
Kowski decom the client growth
accelerator program right here okay I
love working with people every single
day helping them through how they can
become better connectors and
communicators and this is really what it
boils down to is how we can actually
break past burnout because all of this
that I've just mentioned so
far is probably going to be overwhelming
to most people because they've not
learned how
to shrink it down to get more done with
less time and become more
efficient and so one of the number one
things that we have to do is we have to
learn to let go of controlling every
little aspect and becoming and being
such a control freak and a micromanager
over every little aspect of what we
doing and then our brain starts
ruminating and coming up with reasons
why it might not work out this person
might think this this person might not
like me this might not produce results
and we end up living in these wha ifs
that end up happening can I tell you
that living in the wha ifs that might
happen in your business instead of
taking
action and and I've said this and I say
this word very cautiously but it is an
important word it's about having what's
called an exper
experimentation
mindset about the actions that you do in
your business and what does an
experimentation mindset look like from
the outside looking in it can look
slightly
Reckless don't tune me out when I say
that word it might look slightly
Reckless because it might be like okay
we're trying different things out we're
seeing what sticks but the thing is is
that this we're not spending a lot of
our
energy making sure that everything is
perfect and we're moving out of
perfectionism and into momentum okay so
your goal is you want to create momentum
and then you want to develop systems and
habits that are repeatable and
duplicatable that you can actually
predict how much time each action takes
when I launch a campaign I actually know
that we've gotten it down when we're
really clicking on all on firing on all
cylinders about 48 hours from the idea
of having a campaign to put out there to
getting it done I know that when it
comes to creating content like this
right here this video right here how
many of yall want to know how long I
took researching what I'm going to talk
about for this video well I took 21
years to research what I'm going to talk
about in this video but it's so aligned
with what I talk about every single day
with business owners that I actually
just sat down for maybe about 15 20
minutes and thought about a few
different angles and directions that I
want to take and then I pressed record
on the
camera that might sound Reckless to some
people it's not because I know that what
I'm talking about is so strategically
aligned with what I what I teach every
day to my clients what I know works for
people and so there's a direct
authenticity in what I'm
saying that's going to produce quality
and it's learning how to speak and talk
in what's called an extemporaneous
way okay so I don't have to come up with
a bunch of strategies to be able to do
this there's a process to get us into
the zone for that one of my processes is
sometimes I might read a novel I might
go for a walk I might have a snack I
might play with my son for 10 15 minutes
as far as that goes to disconnect my
brain slightly from the task that I have
to do that might be overwhelming me
because what ends up happening is is our
brain when we focus way too hard on one
task you can actually take something
that might only take you 10 15 minutes
of brainstorming and it turns into 5
hours of
overwhelm and this is one of the biggest
things that I find that happens with
people or you might get overwhelmed with
a technology
tool and then we start processing
through beating ourselves up that we're
not smart enough or we don't know how to
do something and all of this and now
we're off on a complete other path
tangent in a dire Direction that's not
actually going to serve us for our goals
but rather distracts
us then this is what I was Finding I was
doing in my life for years is I was
distracting myself in the moments where
I needed to focus all the time when I
didn't feel confident when I felt
uncertain I would try to distract myself
from having to do the action because I
was afraid of what might happen if I
mess up if I make a mistake if I don't
do the right thing as far as as it goes
and so then that ballooned into hours
and hours and hours of working time for
me to get stuff done in my
business and and and quite frankly a big
part of it was I had to stop living in
the past so much I had to stop replaying
all the things that I was afraid of I
had to stop ruminating on potential ways
that things could go wrong and I really
had to align my vision and start
visualizing what I was creating so the
idea was was visualizing things going
well for me I'm overwhelmed by a
Facebook ads campaign it takes me 6
hours to create an ads campaign that's
what used to happen now if I start
visualizing the ads campaign working for
me even if I have no proof or evidence
that it's going to work for me that's
where the experimentation mindset comes
in but I start having hope and
expectancy of it working out well for me
it might only take me 15 minutes to get
done and you might say well Jeremiah
gosh that sounds like a recipe for
disappointment that sounds like a recipe
for being disappointed when things don't
go how you want them
to and I think that's one of the keys is
to get to is to where disappointment is
no longer built up so much in our
mind that it's no longer this sacred um
thing that's on a pedestal that we sort
of try to avoid and also are afraid of
and and it's
like what if things don't go how we want
them to we're experimenting we're trying
things out or testing things out and
again this literally might create
anxiety in you hearing me say this
that's where we have to resolve where is
that anxiety coming from so that we can
learn to calm our nervous system down
because here's what then ends up
happening when you can learn to calm
your nervous system down when you have
that pit in your stomach that's like
okay I'm this is too much it's way too
much when you can learn to literally
have emotional self-control and calm
your nervous system down when that pit
in your stomach starts coming in and
Trust me it happens to me as
well you can learn to hear your
intuition better and your inner voice
better and then you start paying
attention to what does that inner voice
inside of you say that directs you on
where to go is that is that inner voice
directing you to do this and you don't
know why it's directing you to do that
you don't know why it's telling you to
do this but you start being like you
know what I think that I should try that
out and we end up stepping into what I
call the childlike play mindset where we
trust our inner voice instead of just
only being in logic so what what I do is
I learn how
to vacillate
between this is my logical brain right
here and then this is my my heart which
is the inner voice which is like
following where your heart goes as far
as is that go that and I and I literally
I'll vacillate between these two when I
need to if I'm way too focused in the
heart side of things I can be way too
Reckless and not really have a strategy
as far as that goes if I focus way too
much on the strategy and the logic side
I literally start shutting out that
inner voice inside of me that's trying
to point and direct my footsteps as far
as this goes that's trying to say let's
go this way and for me I believe as well
I have faith in God that God comes into
this and even helps give direction
whether you have that Faith or not I
totally understand but this works and
I've and there's literally neuro
neuroscience and biological science
behind this that's connected to when we
can learn how to bring all that anxiety
down and we start listening to the
instincts the intuition the experience
the things that maybe we know but we
don't know how we know them the things
that we feel we just got a gut feeling
about and you start following your gut
more as far as that goes they also say
that the gut has neurotransmitters in it
as far as that goes that there's a
there's a second thinking brain inside
of our gut that can also help direct us
so a lot of this again we don't have
full-on explanations for how this works
there's like massive amounts of
Neuroscience and things that you could
study on this topic but all that to say
is that when you can learn to really
listen to that and you then you get out
of focusing in so much on what you're
not doing right what could go wrong and
a big one is loving yourself self-care
not punishing yourself not beating
yourself up when you're not doing the
right
thing and giving yourself
Grace to mess up that it's okay to make
a mistake that it's okay for things to
not go perfect for you that it's okay
for us to try out just to see what
happens because what ends up happening
is it becomes sort of a stepping stone
approach you might want to get over here
but you're over here the problem is is
that you have to go step one 2 3 4 to
get there and we end up sitting here and
saying well I want to get here so we
don't do anything because we don't want
to step on these Stones right here we're
like I don't think I need to step on
those stages I need to just get here as
far as that goes and so imagine this
imagine that somebody's standing in
front of a pond and they want to get to
this Stone right here and there's a
million dollars over here but they stay
here for five years because they like no
I honestly I don't think that I need to
worry about those three I'm just going
to figure out how I can just Leap Frog
and jump over
here that's what most people do and it
stops them from enjoying the process and
embracing the process as far as that
goes and this is why when we embrace the
process we can actually work
less it's a weird sort of like the uh
The Sword and the stone you remember the
story about like The Sword and the stone
King Arthur he and it's like all the
strong men couldn't pull it out but like
the purest of heart could type of a
thing and like he wasn't the strongest
but it was there's I I always look at it
like that it's like it's like these
contrarian thoughts our brain doesn't
make sense of the fact that actually
going step by step is actually a faster
path to where we're trying to go and
it's less
work it's so interesting but when you
get to the Finish Line every single
business owner tells you it's the same
thing is that when you follow a
stepbystep
process things start to get simpler and
that's exactly what I love to help
people with in my coaching programs
that's exactly what as well we're
hosting an event if you're watching this
right now where I'm actually doing
something on June 5th called create and
launch your sixf figure group coaching
Community offer without burnout it's a
live 2hour training intensive where I'm
going to work with you through building
out your offers building out your
business building out strategically
exactly how to put all the puzzle pieces
together in your business and we do
these often if you're watching this
after June 5th just go to my website
Jeremiah Kowski decom go to the homepage
and you'll see if there's any live
events that we're doing or any other
classes that we might offer or ask me in
the comments below as far as what what
we have that's updated as far as that
goes so what you have to do is you have
to say okay I have all this stuff that I
need to do but what's important to do in
the next seven days and that's your
stepping stone s days s days s days s
days because we can look at this might
be four weeks down the road and you're
like well gosh I just want that to
happen fast for
me and it's just too much work I can't I
can't do all that
work and then we get overwhelmed and we
get burnt out and we're doing things
that we don't really enjoy that we're
not seeing results from and it's because
we're operating often out of unrealistic
expectations for things happening faster
for us as far as that goes than they
than they than they should we're trying
to get results for work that we haven't
done and often that can be where burnout
comes from but the second side of it is
this is that we think that we have to do
all of this work every single day to get
stuff done and what we found is
[Applause]
this is that for most business
owners this is all the work that they're
doing every single day but this is what
actually produces the financial results
and what I encourage people to do is
this is that you might have all of this
stuff that you might think that you need
to do to be successful because you see
uh gurus and stuff like that doing all
this this stuff but really what got them
there was bootstrapping it and doing
this little bit of stuff and then adding
more of those pieces over time as far as
that goes so when you can focus down and
focus in on what is the like
90% that you can
eliminate and what is the
10% that we need to focus on now we've
reduced our amount of working time down
from like a 100 hours down to
10 and so like what are some of these
things some of it could literally be you
spending all this time making your video
content Perfect all this time optimizing
your your message and and and really
dialing in exactly what your funnel
should be and all of that and trying to
make the copy perfect and trying to make
sure that you're received well and and
all of this stuff making sure that you
got all your courses aligned and all
that again all of that's
important one of the biggest problems
that I see people do too as well is
they're like well I'm going to build my
audience first for the next 6 months and
then I'm going to sell a product I'm
going to work for 6 months to create a
product as far as that goes I never see
those people making a
dime they think that that's what they
should do it creates burnout because
they get burnt out by the fact that
they're not producing revenue and so the
number one thing that actually defeats
burnout that most people don't realize
is
this is cash
flow cash flow without working so much
and eliminating the fear of what other
people think about us so that's one of
the biggest reasons why we burn
ourselves out is we feel obligated to do
all of this stuff maybe you got a lot of
things that you got to do f for
fulfillment maybe you're doing a ton of
one-on-one coaching calls maybe you're
spending all this time to do all of this
stuff that's not actually bringing in
cash flow for you and so this is why I
say prioritize the profit
over even all the stuff that quote
unquote produces impact as far as that
goes don't hear me wrong you want to
make impact important but realize that
there might be 90% of all the stuff that
you feel like you need to do every
single day to produce impact that is not
actually creating the impact at the
level that you're thinking and it's
really about 10% of that that you want
to focus on you want to be lean you want
to look at okay if I had 3,000 people
in my coaching business what activities
would I do that's sustainable with 3,000
people would you get on one-on-one calls
with 3,000 people no now in the
beginning you might to gain some clarity
and ideas and get focused in on what are
some of the things that maybe they want
or desire and stuff like that to get on
these different calls but we end up
spending a lot of time doing busy work
that doesn't turn into revenue for us
and so what we really need to do that
turns into revenue for us is we need
to communicate
right with people and this can be
through social
media this can be through
email so that we can connect with them
and this is where we connect with the
hearts of people so that then we can
sell to to
them what our programs are and most
people never get here to where they're
selling they focus in on communication
and connection but they're not actually
learning how to ask the sales question
they're not actually going out there and
Diving deeper into saying hey here's
something that I have to offer that's
for sale for you to buy here's something
for you to register for to sign up for
notice in this video and it might it
might have pissed off a few people
that's not something I'm concerned about
as far as as that goes cuz I know the
right ones that are supposed to be here
are not upset about it when I mentioned
oh I have a live event that I'm doing
right here it's an incredible event I'd
recommend you register for when I
mentioned my coaching program right here
you might say well Jeremiah maybe you
shouldn't have mentioned that you know I
I could go find that on my own as far as
that goes I don't need you to tell me
about that okay listen understand that
that thinking of I don't need to tell
people about what I do is why you're
burnt
out is why you're not making the kind of
money you want to make
make now the flip side is if all you're
doing is selling if all you're doing is
telling people about what you have for
sale nobody's going to want to listen to
you because they're like oh well all you
care about is sales so you got to really
learn to strike a balance of making a
connection and delivering to people what
they want and learning how to do so
without spending a ton of time to have
to do so we think that we have to spend
hours and hours and hours to be able to
create this connection but there's a way
to
communicate where you don't have to OV
explain yourself where you don't have to
defend yourself and try to over process
as far as that goes well you can learn
how to communicate and say more with
less words that's effective and that's
again that's exactly what I coach and
Mentor people on in my accelerator
program for those of you that do want to
jump into this I'd love for you to jump
on our waiting list and I'd love for you
when we do open the doors to this to
join us on this and as well join us for
one of our live events that we are
hosting where I walk you through how do
you create an
offer that actually gets people to buy
from you what an offer does is it
communicates it connects and it sells to
people all at the same time an effective
offer and you want to think in terms of
offers you want to think in terms of
every single material that you put out
there even these YouTube videos every
single piece of material that you put
out there is letting people know about
your offer that you have now it doesn't
have to be as explicit it doesn't have
to be as hardcore or direct your goal is
you want to get people on your email
list and then from there you want to
provide value which then helps them make
a decision that says huh maybe I want to
work with you later and so if you can
help people make that decision that they
want to work with you later and you
don't go in for the jugular and try to
sell them right away it becomes actually
a great experience for everybody all
around and you learn to defeat burnout
because you're not taking all of this
time to get to the point of what you're
trying to get to and you're no longer
feeling guilty about trying to sell to
people and you're no longer feeling like
oh like this is wrong or bad for me to
do this as far as this
goes if you feel like it's wrong or bad
for you to sell to people and you don't
want to connect with people just for the
purpose of selling to them that's an
area that you might need to address
inside of you and really ask yourself
where does that come from why do I feel
bad doing this why do I feel bad showing
up and connecting in order to make money
and be paid what I'm worth in my
business and again it often goes to lack
of self-belief lack of self-esteem not
thinking that we're worthy of success
not thinking that we're worthy of people
actually paying money for what we
offer realize you are worthy of it and
in fact that might be programming that
you've been programmed with that you're
not worthy of that that you're not good
enough that you don't believe in
yourself that you don't think highly of
yourself enough that people would be
blessed to spend money with you so then
what ends up happening is we're chasing
the dollar and we're desperate for it
and that creates burnout instead of
coming from a place of authority where
you establish yourself and you say you
know what we have this value this is
what we have to offer we'd love to work
with you it'd be incredible we can get
you results just like we've helped
thousands of people get results with and
you believe fully like I believe fully
any anyone watching this video right now
is blessed to have gotten to this point
in this video anybody who joins my
coaching program is blessed to be in
that program oh and by the way that's
what our clients tell us too our clients
tell us I Jeremiah I have joined
multiple coaching programs we hear this
all the time I've joined so many
coaching programs and yours is literally
the best that's out there that answers
what exactly what I need and you cover
exactly what's going to get me results
and we help our clients make tens of
thousands of dollars every single month
in there so again if you're watching
this right now love to see you join us
for one of our Live Events would love to
see you in the accelerator program with
me when we do open the doors to it as
far as that goes stay plugged in with
this YouTube channel keep watching the
videos that we have and I want you to
start to learn how to sell and I want
you to start to learn how to get more
results if there's something a topic or
something that maybe I've shared that
you want me to dive deeper into leave a
comment below and let me know i' like to
hear from you about maybe what are some
of the other topics that You' like me to
share or make video content about or
things like that and then we will create
more content based on that so leave me a
comment let me know and we'll dive in
deeper what business are you in tell me
as well what are you working on where
are you stuck let me know where you're
stuck in your business that might also
help us as well let me know what stage
of your business that you like want to
get unstuck in there's no need to be
embarrassed at all and I'll create more
content for that as well to help you and
to help you get results love to work
with you deeper would love to work with
you on a much more intentional level
and I hope that we can have a good one
everybody and we'll talk soon